Menu

Menu

Privacy Policy
==============

### Updated June 2024

### Introduction

At schoolonline.co.uk, we place the highest importance on keeping personal information private. Below in our Privacy Policy (combined with the “[Terms and Conditions](https://www.schoolexams.co.uk/terms-conditions) and other Agreements) we have set out our privacy practices and policies, please carefully read both pages.

### 1\. Information About Us

schoolonline.co.uk (School Reviewer Limited), Registered in England and Wales under company number 08861959 and registered address:  
New Derwent House, 69-73 Theobalds Road, London, England, WC1X 8TA

For any data related concerns please address communications to:  
Email address: [dpo@schoolonline.co.uk](mailto:dpo@schoolonline.co.uk)  
Please add the subject line “Data Access Request” to all emails regarding your data access request.

### 2\. What Does This Notice Cover?

This Privacy Information explains how we use your personal data: how it is collected, how it is held, and how it is processed. It also explains your rights under the law relating to your personal data.

### 3\. What is Personal Data?

Personal data is defined by the General Data Protection Regulation (EU Regulation 2016/679) (the “GDPR”) as ‘any information relating to an identifiable person who can be directly or indirectly identified in particular by reference to an identifier’.

Personal data is, in simpler terms, any information about you that enables you to be identified. Personal data covers obvious information such as your name and contact details, but it also covers less obvious information such as identification numbers, electronic location data, and other online identifiers. The personal data that we use on this site including online ordering is set out in Part 5, below.

### 4\. What Are My Rights?

Under the GDPR, you have the following rights, which we will always work to uphold:

1. The right to be informed about our collection and use of your personal data.
2. The right to access the personal data we hold about you.
3. The right to have your personal data rectified if any data is inaccurate or incomplete.
4. The right to be forgotten, i.e. you can request that we delete, shred or otherwise dispose of any of your personal data that have retained.
5. The right to restrict (i.e. prevent) the processing of your personal data.
6. The right to object to our using your personal data for a particular purpose.
7. The right to data portability. This means that you can ask for a copy of your personal data held by to re-use with another service or business in many cases.
8. Rights relating to automated decision-making and profiling. We do not use your personal data in this way.

Further information about your rights can also be obtained from the Information Commissioner’s Office or your local Citizens Advice Bureau.  
If you have any cause for complaint about our use of your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office.

### 5\. What Personal Data Do You Collect?

We may collect some or all of the following personal data (this may vary according to which of our services you use):

* Name
* Email Address
* Year Level
* School Group
* IP address
* EAL
* When placing an order online our payment gateway provider (Stripe, PayPal or ApplePay) will have your payment information transferred to them through a secure encrypted connection, this data is not stored on our servers, once transferred the data is subject to their own Privacy Policies.

### 6\. How Do You Use My Personal Data?

Under the GDPR, we must always have a lawful basis for using personal data. This may be because the data is necessary for our performance of a contract with you, because you have consented to our use of your personal data, or because it is in our legitimate business interests to use it. Your personal data will be used for one of the following purposes:

* Providing account management facilities
* Providing purchased materials
* Providing advertising of products relevant to you

Within the site there are various locations where you have the option to agree to join our mailing list, you can unsubscribe from our newsletter at any stage or you can request removal from our mailing list by getting in touch with our DPO.

You will not be sent any unlawful marketing or spam. We will always work to fully protect your rights and comply with any and all obligations under the GDPR and the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003, and you will always have the opportunity to opt-out at any time.

### 7\. How Long Will You Keep My Personal Data?

We will not keep your personal data for any longer than is necessary in light of the reason(s) for which it was first collected. Your personal data will, therefore, be kept for the following periods (or, where there is no fixed period, the following factors will be used to determine how long it is kept):

* User account data will be held for a period of 3 years after your last purchase
* Contact Us request data will be held for a period no greater than 3 months
* Desensitised/sanitised (removal of your personal data) financial data about orders will be held for a period of six years from the end of the current financial year, as is legally required.
* Data used during registration for trial period for no greater than 12 months.

### 8\. How and Where Do You Store or Transfer My Personal Data?

We will only store your personal data in the UK. This means that it will be fully protected under GDPR. The security of your personal data is essential to us and we will always strive to protect your data, We take a number of important measures, including the following:

* Encrypted data transfer and storage
* Secure and restricted access to customer data
* Secure paper record shredding and digital data removal

### 9\. Do You Share My Personal Data?

We will not share any of your personal data with any third parties for any purposes, subject to the following important exceptions.

In some limited circumstances, We may be legally required to share certain personal data, which might include yours, if we are ever involved in legal proceedings or complying with legal obligations, a court order, or the instructions of a government authority.

As referenced above, when placing an order on our website your data your payment information will be transferred to Stripe, ApplePay or PayPal through a secure encrypted connection.

Our website developers are based in the UK and Slovenia and adhere to the same policies as School Reviewer Limited. They may from time to time need to access personal data to resolve issues with your account or orders.

### 10\. How Can I Access My Personal Data?

If you want to know what personal data we have about you, you can contact our DPO for details of that personal data and for a copy of it (where any such personal data is held). This is known as a “subject access request”.

All subject access requests should be made in writing and sent to the email or postal addresses shown in Part 11. There is not normally any charge for a subject access request. If your request is ‘manifestly unfounded or excessive’ (for example, if you make repetitive requests) a fee may be charged to cover our administrative costs in responding.

We will respond to your subject access request within 1 month from the date the request is received. Normally, we aim to provide a complete response, including a copy of your personal data within that time. In some cases, however, particularly if your request is more complex, more time may be required up to a maximum of three months from the date we receive your request.

### 11\. How Do I Contact You?

To contact our DPO about anything to do with your personal data and data protection, including to make a subject access request, please use the following details:  
Email address: [dpo@schoolonline.co.uk](mailto:dpo@schoolonline.co.uk)  
Please add the subject line “Data Access Request” to all emails regarding your data access request.

### 12\. Cookies

**What are cookies?**  
Cookies are tiny text files stored on your computer when you visit certain web pages. We use cookies to keep track of what you have in your basket, and to remember you when you return to our site.

To order products, manage your account or watch videos, you need to have cookies enabled – see the section on Managing cookies. If you don’t wish to enable cookies, you’ll still be able to browse the site and use it for research purposes. Most web browsers have cookies enabled, but see Managing cookies for help to turn them on should you need to.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you would prefer not to accept cookies, most browsers will allow you to: (1) change your browser settings to notify you when you receive a cookie, which lets you choose whether or not to accept it; (2) to disable existing cookies; or (3) to set your browser to automatically reject any cookies. However, please be aware that if you disable or reject cookies, some features and services on our sites may not work properly because we may not be able to recognise and associate you with your account. In addition, the offers we provide when you visit us may not be as relevant to you or tailored to your interests.

Please note that cookies can’t harm your computer. We don’t store personally identifiable information such as credit card details in cookies we create. We use cookies to:

* Identify the device that you are using to browse our website, this helps us to display the best version of the website based on your device.
* Identify you as a registered user and define which material you have purchased to enable access.

**Instructions for blocking or allowing cookies in popular web browsing software:**

### 13\. Third Party Links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

### 14\. Changes to this Privacy Notice

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. This may be necessary, for example, if the law changes, or if we change our business in a way that affects personal data protection.

Any changes will be made available via this page on the website, so please check back regularly, we will always start this document with the last update date.

Any dispute or claim arising from the above shall be governed by the laws of the United Kingdom.

**This document is the copyright of School Reviewer Limited**

© Copyright SchoolOnline 2022 | [Terms](https://www.schoolonline.co.uk/terms-conditions/) | [Privacy](https://www.schoolonline.co.uk/privacy/)
